[music]
Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine
and today we've got an
intermediate level lesson
all about going to the beach.
That's right, you know, it's a very popular
thing to do, especially during the summer.
It's hot. You want to
go maybe to the beach
to lay on the sand and
maybe get some color.
Yeah, and also swim in the ocean. Yeah.
Yeah, it's a nice way to cool off
when it's really hot in the summer.
That's right. So we're
going to talk about the
beach and a lot of
vocab that we find related
to this activity. But before
we get into the dialogue,
we have a word for you
on vocabulary preview.
Vocabulary preview.
So the key word today here is jellyfish.
Jellyfish.
So jellyfish is actually an animal, right?
That's right. It's a very dangerous animal.
It's a small little animal.
So these things live in
the water and they often
live in shallow areas
and they can sting you.
That's right. They
look like little plastic
bags with little strings
attached to it and they
just float around. And
if you happen to touch
one, it hurts a lot. Yeah,
it can be very painful.
So jellyfish is our word today.
Let's take a listen to
today's dialogue and we'll be
back in a minute to talk
more about what's going on.
Oh, George, what
a beautiful day it is.
The sun is hot and there are just a
few clouds scattered here and there.
What a perfect day
to be at the beach.
The kids are going to have so much fun
and we'll be able to relax in the sun while
they're playing. It does
seem like the perfect day.
Glad we chose to get out of the
city and enjoy the nice weather.
This looks like
the perfect spot.
Okay, kids, put on your sunscreen while
your mom and I set up camp. You're married.
Help me lay down
these beach towels.
There we go. Can you help
me with the umbrella? Perfect.
Okay, kids. Here's a
beach ball and a frisbee,
a pale and a shovel. I
want to see an impressive
sand castle by the time
we leave. Don't stray too far.
Wait, leave your sandals here or put on
your wet shoes and stay in the shallow area.
I don't want to see you go
any further than that sandbar.
It's too deep out there and
we didn't bring your floaties.
You're back already. The
water was too cold, huh?
I'll tell you a secret.
You see that small pool of water
over there? It'll be warmer in there.
You'll see if you can
find some seashells
or catch some minnows.
Oh, what is that? Jellyfish?
Jeremy, put that down right now.
It could sting you. All
right, great. We're back.
So now I don't want to take
a look at four key words that
we have prepared for you
today on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. First up, we have a
very important thing to bring to the beach,
especially if you're like me and you burn
easily. So this thing is called sunscreen.
Okay, sunscreen. Now
this is a liquid and you
put it on your skin, right?
And this protects you
from the sun. So basically
you put this cream all
over your body to prevent
sunburns, to prevent
burning under the
sun. It's very important.
So it's called sunscreen or
also sometimes called sunblock.
That's right. Okay, very good.
Now we have our sunscreen
and we arrived to the beach
and one of the parents
say, all right, we're
going to set up camp.
Okay, to set up camp.
Well, this might be
confusing because as many
of you know, camp camping, this is an
activity, but we're not actually camping here.
We're just going to be
at the beach for one day.
So to set up camp means to
organize or arrange ourselves in a place.
So it's a colloquial
way of saying we're
going to organize the
area where we're going
to spend the day. We're going
to make ourselves comfortable.
So you set up camp.
So not not necessarily that
you're going to camp there,
but that you're going
to prepare the area.
So this could be used in many
other different areas, right?
That's right. So
sometimes, you know, when
when tickets for really
popular concerts go on sale,
people line up for days
before they can buy the tickets.
Well, if you're in
line, you maybe
want to set up camp. That
means make yourself comfortable,
sit down, bring a book,
open some food packages.
Right. Exactly. So to set
up camp. And well, when
we go to the beach, we
want to sit down or lay
down on the sand. And
in order to do this, we
usually bring along beach
towels. That's right, Marco.
So towels can be
any kind of towel.
You have the towel in your
bathroom or in your kitchen.
Basically, a piece of cloth
that you use to dry yourself.
But the special kind
of towel we bring
to the beach is called,
of course, a beach towel.
Right. These are usually a
much bigger than normal towels.
Yeah, they're
they're very, very big.
And this is usually because
you want to lay down
on the sand on top
of this towel, right?
That's right. Okay. And the
last word that we have for
language takeaway is a beach
umbrella or just an umbrella.
That's right. So maybe
you're lying down
on this big, comfortable,
soft beach towel and
you're afraid of being
under the sun too much.
So an umbrella is a way to
protect yourself from the sun.
It provides shade. That's right.
So it's it's called an
umbrella or usually if you
want to distinguish
between the umbrella you use
for the rain, you can
call it a beach umbrella.
That's right. Okay.
And these are usually
a lot bigger and you
don't actually carry them
around in your hand. You
have to put them into the sand.
That's right. So it
stands alone. Okay.
So four key phrases there
for you on language takeaway.
When we go back, listen to the
dialogue again and we'll be back shortly.
Oh, George, what
a beautiful day it is.
The sun is hot and there are just a
few clouds scattered here and there.
What a perfect day
to be at the beach.
The kids are going to have so much fun
and we'll be able to relax in the sun while
they're playing. It does
seem like the perfect day.
Glad we chose to get
out of the city and enjoy
the nice weather. This
looks like the perfect spot.
Okay, kids, put on your sunscreen
while your mom and I set up camp.
Your Mary, help me lay
down these beach towels.
There we go. Can you help
me with the umbrella? Perfect.
Okay, kids. Here's a
beach ball and a frisbee,
a pale and a shovel. I
want to see an impressive
sand castle by the time
we leave. Don't stray too far.
Wait, leave your sandals
here or put on your wet shoes.
And stay in the shallow area.
I don't want to see you go
any further than that sandbar.
It's too deep out there and
we didn't bring your floaties.
Your back already, the
water was too cold, huh?
I'll tell you a secret.
Do you see that
small pool of water over
there? It'll be warmer in there.
You'll see if you can find some
seashells or catch some minnows.
Ah! What is that? Jellyfish? Jeremy, put
that down right now. It could sting you.
Not on me. Alright, we're
back. So now we have
five more words that
we're going to take a look at
in language takeaway
part two. Okay, so there
are lots of fun things
to do at the beach.
And today we're not
going to be talking about
all of them because
there are too many things,
but one fun activity
is playing frisbee.
That's right, frisbee. So
this is a thing that it's an
object, a frisbee, or
you also play frisbee.
That's right. So a frisbee
itself is usually made of
plastic and it's like
a plate and it's very
light and you throw
it to your friends and it
seals through the air.
Right. It kind of flies along
the air and then somebody
else has to catch it.
That's right. So you can play frisbee or
throw the frisbee. It's very popular with
people playing frisbee
with their dogs, right?
You throw the frisbee
and the dog chases it.
Dogs love frisbee. Alright,
another great activity
that usually we do
when we go to the beach
is we build sand castles.
Okay, so I'm a master
sandcastle builder. I'm a
really big fan of this activity.
Really? Basically you use water and sand
to create castles. Right. And obviously you
have to use tools like shovels and buckets.
Otherwise it might look kind of funny.
And this is actually such
a popular activity that
there are even
competitions at times.
People will not only build
castles or houses or structures,
but maybe a statue of
some sort or an animal or
different things. That's
right. Or people. Yeah.
So sandcastle. Okay. And
well, whenever we go to
the beach, the ocean can
be a little bit dangerous.
And that's why in the
dialogue, one of the parents
told their kids to stay in
the shallow area of the water.
That's right. So shallow
is it describes depth.
So how deep something is.
Something is shallow. It's not very
deep. Okay. So there's very little water.
Okay. But if there's a lot of water,
maybe if you swim and you can't touch your
feet on the ground,
we call that deep.
So shallow is very low water
and deep is lots and lots of water.
Okay. Very good. So you'll
usually find this in the ocean.
If you go further
further further in,
it'll get deeper and deeper
and deeper and more dangerous.
Right. And this is why the mom also
told the kid to not pass that sandbar.
That was ahead. Okay.
Sandbar, this is a piece of sand
that basically rises
very high in the water.
So usually when you're on
the beach and you go into
the water and it gets
deeper and deeper and then
all of a sudden it gets high
again. And there's more sand.
Right. And so that part
that you can stand on
that sand out in the water
that's called a sandbar.
It's almost like a little
island. Yeah, exactly.
And as you said, usually
it gets deeper deeper
than you have the
sandbar. So it gets higher.
But usually if you pass the
sandbar, it's going to get
really deep all of a
sudden. That's right.
So that's why the mother
doesn't want her child to go
past the sandbar.
Right. And well, if you're
ever swimming in a
swimming pool in the ocean,
it's always a good idea
if you don't know how to
swim well or if you have
children to take along
little floaties. Okay, floaties.
I like this word. A floaties
are plastic rings that you put
around your arms or maybe
around your stomach and
they're filled with air.
Right. So when you go on
the water, they help
you float. Exactly.
So this is very a very common
thing to put on children
because they don't
know how to swim well.
You put them little floaties
on their arms or around
their stomachs and then
they can just float and
they won't drown.
That's right. A floaties.
Very good. So a lot of key
words there are related to
the fun of going to the
beach. Why don't we go
back, listen to the dialogue
for the very last time.
Oh, George, what
a beautiful day it is.
The sun is hot and
they're just a few clouds
scattered here and there.
What a perfect day to
be at the beach. The kids
are going to have so much
fun and we'll be able
to relax in the sun while
they're playing. It does
seem like the perfect day.
Glad we chose to get
out of the city and enjoy
the nice weather. This
looks like the perfect spot.
Okay, kids, put on your sunscreen while
your mom and I set up camp. You're married.
Help me lay down these
beach towels. There we go.
Can you help me with
the umbrella? Perfect.
Okay, kids. Here's a
beach ball and a frisbee,
pale and a shovel. I want to see an
impressive sand castle by the time we leave.
Don't straight too far.
Wait, leave your sandals here
and put on your wet shoes.
And stay in the shallow area.
I don't want to see you go
any further than that sand bar.
It's too deep out there and we didn't
bring your floaties. You're back already.
The water was too cold,
huh? I'll tell you a secret.
You see that small
pool of water over there?
It'll be warmer in there.
You'll see if you can
find some seashells
or catch some minnows.
Ah, what is that? Jellyfish?
Jeremy, put that down
right now. It could
sting you. All right, so
beach activities. You say you're
a master sand castle builder.
I love building sand castles.
I won't say that
I'm very good at it.
Maybe not a professional, but I
do, I do a pretty good sand castle.
Do you like getting
buried in the sand?
I love it, although
it also scares me.
Have you ever had someone maybe
cover you a sand and then you can't move?
Yeah. Yeah, so
it's a little bit scary.
Obviously, I'm not
very comfortable with
having my head covered,
but some people even do that.
They cover their entire
body, head to toe.
How do they breathe?
And they have a straw out of
their mouth to breathe.
Wow. Now, I actually love
going to the beach,
and it's relaxing.
It's really fun, but I don't
really enjoy it going when
there are a lot of people.
Because I like to relax
on the beach, but when there are too many
people, you know, they're running around.
They're kids running around
and it's not very relaxing.
Yeah, here you go. But
swimming in the ocean is
also very dangerous,
right? It can be. It can be.
So we recommend you
go places where there are
lifeguards on duty or that you go with an
expert swimmer lifeguards. It's very good.
That's all we've got though
for today. We hope you've
enjoyed this lesson, and we hope you're
excited about the upcoming summer months.
If you have any questions or
comments, please do visit our
website, EnglishPod.com. All
right. We'll see you guys there.
Bye. Bye.